ILGWU Research Department Collected Documents 5780/056
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Incl. copy of ltr. from Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Mfrs., Inc. to Gov. Franklin D. Roosevelt.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Summary of provisions in new agreement; agreement bet. Youthmaid Cloak Co. & Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union; announcements re agreement from Industrial Council.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Lists of members of Industrial Council & Union cloak shops in all districts.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Lists of shops.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Lists of strike halls & committees.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Picket Committee report.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  Ltrs. to The Day & other papers.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  Shop chairman resolutions.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  Strike call & GEB announcement of decision re strike & results of strike referendum.
- N.Y. Cloakmakers' Strike, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  Plans of Speakers & Entertainment Committees; lists of speakers and hall assignments.
- New York Dressmakers' Strike, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Printed material issued by Speakers & Entertainment Committees; incl. Speaker's Guide.
- N.Y. Dressmakers' Strike, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  "Memorandum of Understanding Reached in Conference Between the Affiliated Association and the Union."
- N.Y. Dressmakers' Strike, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  "Facts About the Dress Strike."
- N.Y. Dressmakers' Strike, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  "Itemized Report of Distribution Committee of the Joint Food Relief Committee of the Striking Dressmakers."
- N.Y. Dressmakers' Strike, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  Strike Committee appointments lists; printed material for speakers by Speakers Committee.
- N.Y. Dressmakers' Strike, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  Incl. Speakers Comm. report.
- New York Garment Industry, 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Lists of shops, jobbers, designers, Industrial Council members, employees; "Report of Investigation of Phila. Cloak Union."
- N.Y. Garment Industry. (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  Union and non-union shops in the Bronx, Manhattan, Brooklyn, East New York and out-of-town.
- Nineteen-nine Strike, NYC, 1909-1910 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Ltr. re police & strikers from Miles M. Dawson (chief counsel), Ladies' Waist Makers' Union; questions re police conduct.
- Nineteen-ten Strike, NYC, 1910 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  The Great Revolt. Order continuing preliminary injunction in case of Max H. Schwarcz against ILGWU (Aug. 27, 1910).
- Correspondence, A-L, 1912-1914 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  I.c.w. Louis Brandeis & Julius Henry Cohen.
- Correspondence, M-Z, 1915-1917 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Boston, Board of Grievances, 1913-1914 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Incl. correspondence. bet. Boston Ladies' Garment Manufacturers Association & Boston Dress and Waist Manufacturers Association; reports from Union office re complaints.
- Boston, Bd. of Grievances, 1913-1914 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Minutes (April 26, 1913, June 4, 1914).
- Boston, Conference, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Minutes of conference bet. M. & C. Skirt Co. & ILGWU at City Club (Aug. 21).
- Chicago, Board of Arbitration, 1915-1917 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  Report of Bd. of Arbitration (Sept. 24, 1915) & modification by Julian Mack (Aug. 21, 1917).
- New York City, Children's Dresses, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  Agreements bet. Children's Dress Mfrs. Assoc. & Locals 10, 50 & 58 (Mar. 4th).
- NYC, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1910 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Draft of demands.
- NYC, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Decisions of Bd. of Arbitration (Jan. 21, Feb. 5 & 6).
- NYC, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  "Memorandum of Points to be Presented to the Board of Arbitration re Wage Increase" (15 pp).
- NYC, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  Minutes of Bd. of Arbitration meeting of Assoc. & Union (Feb. 3-4, pp. 5-125).
- NYC, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  Statements by Louis Brandeis before Bd. of Arbitration.
- NYC, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  "Before the Council of Conciliation in the Cloak and Suit Industry. Statement in behalf of the ILGWU and Jt. Bd. of Cloak and Skirtmakers Unions" (39 pp.), submitted by Morris Hillquit (July 13); decision re preferential hiring and price settlements by Council.
- NYC, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  July 21, 1915. Council of Conciliation transcript (pp. 479-634).
- NYC, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  March 4, 1915. Bd. of Grievances minutes re A. Gershel & Co. & other matters.
- NYC, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  Dec. 19, 1913. Minutes of conferences bet. Union & mfrs. re apprentices in cutting trade (47 pp).
- NYC, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  "A Statement from the Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers Protective Association" (16 pp) re "existing condition," in the industry; Morris Hillquit's remarks on impending lockout (April 26).
- NYC, Dress and Waist Industry, 1917-1919 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  Incl. "Proposal by the Dress and Waistmakers Association for suggested changes in the Agreement between Association, the ILGWU & its Locals" (1919); "Protocol of Peace Between the Dress & Waist Manufacturers assoc. & the ILGWU" (Jan. 1917 -Jan. 1919).
- NYC, Dress and Waist Industry, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Complaints to Board of Arbitration by Dress and Waist Manufacturers Assoc. and Union.
- NYC, Dress and Waist Industry, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Oct. 1913. Bd. of Arbitration complaint, ILGWU vs. Dress & Waist Manufacturers assoc. (draft).
- NYC, Dress and Waist Industry, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Bd. of Arbitration complaint, Dress & Waist Mfrs. Assoc. vs. ILGWU.
- NYC, Dress and Waist Industry, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Extracts of Bd. of Arbitration decisions (Mar. 19 & Apr. 12).
- NYC, Dress and Waist Industry, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  Rulings and Recommendations of the Bd. of Arbitration in the matter of legal holidays.
- Ladies' Dress and Waistmakers' Assoc. Complaints, 1913-1924 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Ladies' Dress and Waistmakers' Assoc. Complaints. [folder 1 of 2], 1914 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Ladies' Dress and Waistmakers' Assoc. Complaints. [folder 2 of 2], 1914 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Ladies' Dress and Waistmakers' Assoc. Complaints., 1914-1915 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Ladies' Dress and Waistmakers' Assoc. Complaints. [folder 1 of 2], 1915 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Ladies' Dress and Waistmakers' Assoc. Complaints. [folder 2 of 2], 1915 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Joint Board. Grievance Committee. Minutes of Meetings., 1914 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- NYC, Dress and Waist Industry, 1914 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Minutes of conferences of Bd. of Grievances.
- NYC, Dress and Waist Industry, 1913 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  Test rates under the Protocol; ltr. from "Dress & Waist Mfrs. Assoc. to Bd. of Grievances" (Aug. 5, 1913, 11 pp); "Charges made by Dress & Waist Mfrs. Assoc. in relation to stoppages of work on May 1, 1913" (Oct. 6, 19 pp).
- NYC, Dress and Waist Industry, 1912-1913 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Minutes of meetings bet. Dress & Waist Mfrs. Assoc. & the ILGWU.
- NYC, Dress and Waist Industry, 1913 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  Ltr. & memo from N.I. Stone, (wage Scale Bd.), of violations of Protocol since its inception.
- NYC, Dress and Waistmakers, 1914 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  Minutes of meeting of Wage Scale Board (July 8) with report & recommendation of N.I. Stone.
- NYC, Joint Board of Sanitary Control, 1911-1923 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Incl. reports, correspondence., "A Year of the Protocol" (The American Cloak and Suit Review, Sept. 1911).
- Philadelphia, 1916 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Jan. 19, 1916. Minutes of meeting and decision of Bd. of Arbitration.
- Miscellaneous, Protocol of Peace, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  Incl. list of employees in Union office; members of Executive Bd. Comm., Jt. Grievance Bd. Comm., & Wage Scale Bd. Comm.
- Miscellaneous, Protocol of Peace. (n.d.) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  Handwritten notes on the history of the Protocol.
- Research Department, ILGWU, 1921 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Corres. with other unions re cost of living and earnings.
- Research Dept., ILGWU, 1913-1921 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Incl. studies on wages & hours among garment workers (1915-21).
- Research Dept., ILGWU, 1915-1920 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Memoranda on earnings of workers in various segments of the Cloak Industry? wages for week-workers in the Cloak and Suit Industry.
- Research Dept., ILGWU, 1921 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Memorandum concerning wage rates of workers in the cloak and suit shops controlled by the N.Y. Jt. Bd, of Cloakmakers; incl. reports by various departments of the Jt. Bd.
- Research Dept., ILGWU, 1920 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  Report on Cost-of-Living Investigation (35 pp); "Memorandum Concerning Increase in the Cost-of-Living Jan-July 1920;" memorandum on cost-of-living increases in various areas of NYC.
- Research Dept., ILGWU, 1919-1922 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Statistical data & wage studies.
- Research Dept., ILGWU, 1919-1922 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Scrapbook, 1920-1929 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  Leaflets & brochures relating to left-right struggle in garment industry.
- Shop Chairmen, N.Y. Cloak and Dress Industry, 1926-1927 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Meetings.
- Trade Union Immigration Bureau, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Unemployment Insurance Fund, NYC Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1920-1927 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  Incl. Regulation for Unemployment Insurance Fund set up in NYC (Feb. 25, 1925); memo to GEB concerning unemployment insurance problems (Nov. 15, 1920).
- Unemployment Insurance Fund, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  A Brief Survey prepared for ILGWU by Alfred L. Bernheim, Labor Bureau, Inc.
- Unions, 1920-1933 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  Reports & press releases.
- Unity House, 1923-1935 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  Incl. reports (1923); "The Unity News" (Aug. & Sept. 1935)
- Miscellaneous Documents, 1910-1948 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  Incl. chart of provisions in agreements (1910-22); no-strike, no-lockout clauses (1910-48); handwritten demand for resignation of John Dyche & Abraham Rosenberg by Jt. Bd.; list of individuals at Supreme Court (Mar. 21, 1916); minutes of Social Welfare Section, Women's City Club (n.d).
- Text digitized from the collection. (Box 14)